shopkick.com 2019-09-15

# Shopkick | shopkick® Privacy Policy

Welcome to shopkick! 

We greatly respect your privacy, and this Privacy Policy is designed and created in that spirit! This Privacy Policy applies to all Users and visitors of the shopkick Program, and describes our information policies and procedures.

* * *

Shopkick, Inc.  (together, and with our parent corporations, subsidiaries and affiliates, “shopkick,” “we,” or “us”) is on a mission to become your premier shopping companion, anytime and anywhere. 

This Privacy Policy governs the collection, use, and disclosure of the information we collect and receive from your use, access, and all interactions with the shopkick mobile application (“Application”), any of shopkick’s services (the “Services”), the shopkick.com website, and any other website associated with shopkick or pages where this Privacy Policy is displayed and accessible (collectively, “Website”) (together, the Website, Application and Services are the “shopkick Program”). Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our [Terms of Service](https://www.shopkick.com/terms-of-service).

## Information Collection and Use

### Information Collection

We collect: 

  *     * Personal Information

  *     * Non-Personally Identifiable Information

  *     * Device Information – Usage Technologies 

  *     * Credit Card Transaction Data

  * Purchase Information
  * Other Information from Third Parties

To provide the shopkick Program, we need information from you. The following are categories of information we collect: 

**Personal Information**

When you use the shopkick Program, we may ask that you provide us with personally identifiable information—information about you that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information we may collect includes your name, phone number(s), email address, home address, and if you elect to participate in certain parts of our Services, payment card numbers, and/or third-party account information (e.g. store loyalty program information, PayPal, Venmo, banking information, etc.). We may also collect information about your preferences and interests.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

When you use the shopkick Program on your mobile phone, computer, or other device(s), our servers may record non-personally identifiable information—information that cannot identify you by itself (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”) such as: (i) information your device sends or transmits, including your device type, your device ID number (for example, your UDID), user settings, and your geographic location (if you consent) (“Device Information”); (ii) information about your use of the shopkick Program, such as offers viewed and/or used, stores visited, information you entered; (iii) search terms you used, or which referring/exit pages brought you to our page, and date/time information, (iv) demographic information you provide, such as your gender or date of birth, (v) information about or from another content delivery platform; and (vi) information derived from such above information and other sources such as entries and offers viewed on either our website or a third-party website, our social media presence, or other information provided by third parties.

In addition, to make the shopkick Program useful in particular locations, we use location technology, such as GPS, our shopkick beacon devices (“shopBeacon” or “beacon”), and other geolocation or presence technologies.  These technologies are found in various locations and broadcast signals that your device may receive, assuming you adjust your device settings to receive such signals such as, by enabling location services. When your device transmits location information, the Application or Website alerts you about available offers, rewards, an item previously liked at a store, or other information we deem useful. To make the Application and shopkick Program operate efficiently, shopkick may also collect other information based on signals from a shopBeacon, for example, the strength of the signal between the shopBeacon and the device and/or the duration the device is near the beacon, including when the Application is in the background or not actively running on your device.

**Cookies, Pixels, and other Usage Technology**

To collect, maintain and use certain Device Information, we may use session ID and persistent “cookies,” data collection tags or directives such as “pixel tags,” Javascript scripts, API calls, and/or other storage on your device (individually or collectively, “Usage Technology”). To learn more about different types of Usage Technology, please visit our [Advertising and Your Choices](https://www.shopkick.com/advertising-and-your-choices) page.

**Credit Card Transaction Data**

If you choose to participate in the Kicks for Purchases program, we will receive information about transactions you make at select merchants including the merchant’s name, location, the date and time of the purchase, the transaction amount, the purchased items and other potentially personal information about you (“Transaction Data”). If you explicitly consent (or ‘opt-in’) to participate in the Kicks for Purchases program, the Transaction Data is received from banks or from credit or debit card networks or issuers (“Transaction Providers”).

**Purchase Information**

If you choose to make purchases through or access the Kicks for Receipts program, the mCommerce or eCommerce feature(s) in the shopkick Program, use certain merchants, or otherwise make any purchases through the shopkick Program, shopkick may receive information about you and your purchases from these sources, including the merchant and store names, the store location, the date and time of your purchase, the transaction amount, the items you purchased, and possibly other information used to make your purchase (“Purchase Information”).

**Other Information from Third Parties**

We may also receive information about you from service providers, our partners, merchants, or other third parties, such as your preferences and interests, device information when you download a mCommerce store application originating from the shopkick Program, make an online purchase originating from the shopkick Program, or your account information for specific third-party providers if they are integrated with the shopkick Program (e.g. store loyalty program information, PayPal, Venmo, etc.), for example when redeem your kicks, or otherwise when such third parties do business with us. Information we receive from such third parties are subject to the limitations of the privacy policies of those third parties. We also receive information about you that is publicly available, such as when you submit information to a blog, chat room, or social network(s). We encourage you to read the privacy policies for those third parties. 

### Information Usage

Subject to the restrictions described in this Privacy Policy and applicable law, we use information about you only for purposes related to shopkick’s business, including to:

  *     * Communicate with you and provide information to you about shopkick’s products and services.

  *     * Update the shopkick Program and improve content and user experience.

  *     * Help you and others discover the shopkick Program. 

  *     * Prepare and perform demographic studies. 

  * If permitted by the applicable Transaction Provider, perform benchmarking, advertising, marketing, performance and promotional studies.

To provide the shopkick Program to you, we use information about you. The following are explanations of some of the ways we use your information: 

**Personal Information**

  *     * Administer, improve, and optimize the shopkick Program. 
      *         * For example, if you are invited to the shopkick Program by your friend through our invitation program we may at times contact you through such specified methods. You and the invited friend must give consent to receive such autodialed or prerecorded message calls, and/or general communication. 
      * Similarly, we may occasionally run sweepstakes, contests, surveys, or other special promotions in which we ask you for Personal Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information (e.g., a zip code, age, or income level) in order to administer contests and other promotions about the shopkick Program or a third-party. We may also use information available and/or provided to contact participants of such contests and promotions

  *     * Personalize your experience with the shopkick Program. 

  *     * Provide you with software updates and/or product announcement.

  * Better understand your needs and interests, and provide you with further information and offers we believe you may find useful or interesting, such as targeted advertising and promotional campaigns.

To contact you, we may at times send emails, texts or SMS, push notifications, or autodialed or prerecorded message calls or text messages at the telephone number(s) or email addresses you provide to us. Standard telephone minute and text charges may apply. At any time, you may opt-out of receiving future communications of these kinds by following the unsubscribe instructions in each promotional communication, or simply by declining to take part in the shopkick Program.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

We may use Non-Personally Identifiable Information, including geolocation and location presence information for a variety of purposes, including to analyze trends through aggregated demographic information and other information about users, and administer, improve and optimize the shopkick Program. Specifically, offering rewards based on your location or presence in a store, providing reminders of items previously liked, showing the highest-rated deals, sales or interesting items in a certain area. To present these offers, we use the signal of our shopBeacon devices (or another geolocation or presence technology), which are located in various places, such as above the entrance to a store. Those devices broadcast signals that can be received by a device on which the Application is installed or the shopkick Program is accessed. When the device receives the shopBeacon signal, you may receive a message about the shopkick Program, such as available rewards or a reminder about an item previously liked. To avoid geolocation data from being used or received by shopkick Program, either while the Website or Application are in the background or not currently running on your device, you can switch off notifications near or at stores in the Settings of the Application at any time, or adjust your device settings. 

**Cookies, Pixels and other Usage Technology**

Usage Technology allows us to do the following: (i) make your interactions with the shopkick Program easier and personalized; (ii) save information relating to your Account and/or activity for future interactions with the shopkick Program; (iii) better understand how you interact with the shopkick Program, and monitor aggregate usage by you and other shopkick users; (iv) monitor web traffic routing on the Services; (v) enable certain features of the Services; (vi) count users who visited certain websites and pages within websites, used applications or features; (vii) analyze the behavior of users of our websites and application; and (viii) determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns and improve the overall shopkick Program. Third party advertisers on the shopkick Program may also place or read cookies on your browser. At any time, you may instruct your device to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from websites you visit by changing your device’s settings. Please understand that if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use all portions or all functionality of the shopkick Program. We may also use Device Information from Usage Technology together with both demographic or psychographic information we collected, and third-party analysis partners to anonymously analyze usage patterns of users and serve tailored advertisements to you.

**Credit Card Transaction Data**

By registering your payment card, you authorize your payment card network (e.g. MasterCard/Visa/Amex) to monitor activity on your payment card and to provide information to shopkick regarding your purchase and return transactions (e.g. unique user identification associated with your payment card, transaction amount, date and time and merchant name and location) to enable your card-linked offer(s). For program offers that provide rewards based on a specific item purchase at a participating merchant, shopkick may provide such information to enable that merchant the ability to determine eligibility. We use the Transaction Data from Transaction Providers for the following purposes: (i) to administer the Kicks for Purchases program; (ii) to determine your eligibility in the Kicks for Purchases program; (iii) to match data from your payment card you linked to the Application with transactions under the Kicks for Purchases program; (iv) to provide you with kicks or other rewards; (v) to analyze the usage and effectiveness of the Kicks for Purchases program; and (vi) to improve and optimize the Services. If you unlink your card account number(s) from your Kicks for Purchases profile, shopkick will no longer request your Transaction Data, and your Transaction Provider will no longer share such information.

**Please note that if you uninstall the application without first unlinking your payment card, shopkick will continue to receive transaction data for a period of up to one hundred (100) days after you uninstall. This data will only be used as described above in the “use of transaction information” section set forth in the  **[ **Kicks for Purchases Terms and Conditions for MasterCard cards**](http://app2.shopkick.com/shopkick/html/buy_and_collect_mc_cc_terms_and_conditions.html) **  or in the **[ **Kicks for Purchases Terms and Conditions for Visa cards**](http://app2.shopkick.com/shopkick/html/buy_and_collect_terms_and_conditions.html) **  and as described in this Privacy Policy.**

**Purchase Information**

We use Purchase Information to: (i) administer, improve and optimize the shopkick Program; (ii) determine your eligibility for kicks; (iii) match your Personal Information with transactions; (iv) provide you with kicks or other rewards; (v) analyze the usage and effectiveness of the shopkick Program; and (vi) to the extent permitted by stores or applicable third parties, analyze trends and deliver tailored advertising.

**Other Information from Third Parties**

We may use information from third parties to administer, update, personalize the shopkick Program, award rewards from your purchases with our partners and select merchants, invite you to the shopkick Program (at the request of your friend(s)), communicate with you, and present relevant offers.

### Information Disclosure

Except in limited circumstances that are set out in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose any Personal Information to third parties. Before shopkick transfers information – both Personal Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information – to a third-party, we confirm they adopted, are subject to, or are contractually obligated to comply with the principles and objectives of this Privacy Policy. **   **

To provide the shopkick Program to you, and comply with applicable laws or legal requests, we may disclose information about you. The following are explanations of some of the ways we disclose your information: 

**At Your Request**

We may disclose your information at your request, whether through the Application, or otherwise through the shopkick Program, such as: 

  *     * If you are invited to the shopkick Program by your friend through our invitation program. Your information will be viewable by the friend who invited you to the shopkick Program, and you may be able to view your friend’s information through the shopkick Program.

  *     * If you request or offer services through our partnerships or promotional offerings from a third-party (e.g. completing surveys and quizzes, signing up for new services, etc.). 

  * When you submit information and communicate with us through a public forum (e.g. social media, features within the shopkick Program, blogs, etc.).

**Transaction Providers, Merchants and Store Partners**

If you chose to participate in the Kicks for Purchases program, we share the Transaction Data and payment card information you entered with the appropriate Transaction Provider. We may also share Transaction Data with select merchants to facilitate the awarding of kicks (only to those merchants that agree to only use the Transaction Data to facilitate the awarding of kicks). 

In addition, when you make purchases through the shopkick Program and use similar features (e.g. mCommerce), you agree Purchase Information may be shared with participating stores, merchants and other relevant third parties. Similarly, when you participate in the Kicks for Receipts program, you agree shopkick may use Purchase Information and other information derived from your participation, to award kicks, deduct kicks, validate offer eligibility, enable offer redemption, and/or provide reporting to merchants and other third parties. 

**Third-Party Service Providers**

We may disclose information to third-party service providers we use to perform various tasks, including data storage, consolidation, retrieval, analysis, effective management customer information, and help communicating with you. These third parties are only given access to information needed to perform their support functions, and are prohibited from using it for other purposes. These third-party service providers include affiliated and unaffiliated service providers in the United States, Europe and other jurisdictions.

**Third-Party Business Partners**

We may disclose information with our third-party business partners, such as marketing, advertising, and analytics companies for various reasons, including to advertise, display relevant content, products and services that you may find useful. To opt out of this sharing, please visit our [Marketing and Advertising](https://app.shopkick.com/marketing_data_opt_out) page. We may also disclose information to our third-party partners to audit the delivery and performance of advertisements. These third-party partners also collect information about you from their cookies, pixel tags, and other Usage Technology placed within the shopkick Program, or otherwise across different websites and applications. To learn more about this type of disclosure and advertising please visit [Advertising and Your Choices](https://www.shopkick.com/advertising-and-your-choices) page.

**Group Companies and Business Transfers**

We may share information with our affiliates, parent or group companies so they may assist us with providing the shopkick Program. Additionally, as our business continues to grow and change, we might restructure, buy, or sell subsidiaries or business units. In these transactions, customer information is often one of the transferred assets, remaining subject to promises made in the then prevailing privacy policy. Also, in the event shopkick, or substantially all of its assets or stock are acquired, transferred, disposed of (in whole or part and including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings), customer information will, as a matter of course, be one of the transferred assets.

**Legal Processes**

We may disclose your information to third parties to as may be required by law, regulatory authorities, or legal process, for example to: 

  *     * Protect the rights, property, safety, confidentiality, or reputation of shopkick or Users. 

  *     * Enforce our terms and conditions. 

  *     * Prevent fraud or cybercrime. 

  * Permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

### Advertising and Your Choices

**Cookies**

The shopkick Program uses cookies and other Usage Technology to help us understand your interests, and administer our Services. We consider information gathered from Usage Technology Non-Personally Identifiable Information. To learn more about how to monitor your device’s use of cookies please visit our [Advertising and Your Choices](https://www.shopkick.com/advertising-and-your-choices) page. Please understand that if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use all portions or all functionality of the shopkick Program. 

**Do Not Track**

Do not track is a signal-based technology and privacy setting that allows users to alerts websites, including third-party advertisers, that you do not want to be tracked. At this time, we do not respond to Do Not Track browser settings and signals. To generally learn more about Do Not Track, please visit our [Advertising and Your Choices](https://www.shopkick.com/advertising-and-your-choices) page.

**Personalized Advertisements**

Cookies and other Usage Technology allow us and third-party advertisers to personalize your experience with the shopkick Program and on third-party webpages. To learn more about personalized advertisements (online-based advertisements) please visit our [Advertising and Your Choice](https://www.shopkick.com/advertising-and-your-choices)s page.

### Links to Third Party Sites

The shopkick Program may contain links or API’s (e.g. data or content exchange interfaces) to external services or websites of other companies or merchants, such as making purchases online. If you click on a button, banner ad, or other type of third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s resources. The fact that we may link to or incorporate online stores’ or a merchant’s services, functionality, or website, or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement, is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party services, functionality, websites or other resources, including their use of personal information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information to a third party. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit to learn more about their privacy practices. These other parties may place their own cookies or other files on your computer or device, collect data or solicit personal information from you.

### Children’s Information

The shopkick Program is not directed to children. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 14. If you are a parent or guardian that has become aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information without your consent, please contact us. If we become aware that a member is under the age of 14 and has provided us with Personal Information without verifiable parental consent, we will delete such information from our files.

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to obtain a list of specific types of your Personal Information disclosed to third party direct marketers during the preceding calendar year. Along with the types of Personal Information disclosed, you are entitled to the identity of any third party businesses with whom we have disclosed Personal Information. To receive a copy of this disclosed information, please contact us at [myprivacy@shopkick.com](mailto:myprivacy@shopkick.com) or mail us at the address below with the subject line “Request For California Privacy Rights.”

### Change or Delete Your Information

You may review, update, correct or delete your Personal Information in your Account by contacting us or by making the appropriate modifications in the Application. If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated.  
Make these changes in the Application by clicking on Settings menu. To unlink a Payment Card in the Application, follow these steps: go to “Linked cards” under the Settings menu, tap on “Edit” and select the card you would like to unlink, then tap “Unlink Card”.  
If you would like us to delete your Account and/or remove your records from our system, please contact us and we will delete your account within 45 days if we do not have any legal obligation to retain the record.

### Security

We employ administrative and electronic measures designed to safeguard and protect your information from unauthorized access and disclosure. In addition, we periodically review and enhance our security and privacy practices as needed. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur we use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent this. It is also important for you to guard against unauthorized access to your passwords and the unauthorized use of your computer.

### International Data

If you are outside the United States, your information will be stored and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Our Privacy Policy and its protection applies to your data. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, shopkick collects Personal Information in the United States and processes it there. Your submission of such information represents your agreement to this collection, storage and processing.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We are committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations governing the collection and use of personal information. From time to time, shopkick will review its collection, use, and disclosure practices in order to assure that we are complying with our Privacy Policy and all applicable laws and regulations. If we make material changes our Privacy Policy, we will issue an updated version of this Privacy Policy with an updated date legend and/or notify you via email, the Website, Application or by other appropriate means prior to the change becoming effective if it is a significant change. You should review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are familiar with any changes to it. If you do not consent to any changes to our Privacy Policy and as a result you would like us not to use or hold Personal Information about you in accordance with the revised terms, you may notify us here so we can discontinue your account, or you may discontinue your use of the shopkick Program.

## Contact Us

We are always trying to make shopkick’s services better. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [myprivacy@shopkick.com](mailto:myprivacy@shopkick.com). You can also contact us at 2317 Broadway Street, Redwood City, CA 94063.

If you would like to change your email unsubscribe setting, please follow this link:  
[http://app.shopkick.com/shopkick/v1/user/show_email_unsubscribe](http://app.shopkick.com/shopkick/v1/user/show_email_unsubscribe).

We hope you will enjoy using shopkick.

Last Updated: February 14, 2018
